A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Secretary of Health and Human Resources, 2005-2010
Library of Virginia
- Series VI. Legislative Files, 2006-2009., Extent: 10.35 cu. ft. (24 boxes).
  Contains legislative packets submitted to and reviewed by the Secretary of Health and Human Resources during each General Assembly session. Each file usually contains enrolled bill reviews, legislative action summaries, and the text of the bill. The enrolled bill reviews and legislative action summaries contain information on affected constituents, agency analysis of the bill, and recommendations for changes, support, or rejection. In some cases, there is limited correspondence about the bill, usually in the form of Post-It notes or email. Also included are several folders containing legislative proposals from agencies under the purview of the Secretary of Health and Human Resources, usually grouped into one binder. These files contain summaries of the various proposals, notes about funding, and impact statements.
  Bill files are arranged chronologically by session year and then numerically within. Miscellaneous legislative files are arranged alphabetically.
  - 2006 House and Senate Bills
    - HJ13 - HJ96. (Box 063, Folder 1)
    - HJ97 - HJ167. (Box 063, Folder 2)
    - HB13 - HB73. (Box 063, Folder 3)
    - HB74 - HB151. (Box 063, Folder 4)
    - HB171 - HB227. (Box 063, Folder 5)
    - HB229 - HB299. (Box 063, Folder 6)
    - HB300 - HB351. (Box 063, Folder 7)
    - HB352 - HB388. (Box 063, Folder 8)
    - HB395 - HB425. (Box 063, Folder 9)
    - HB426 - HB555. (Box 063, Folder 10)
    - HB568 - HB583. (Box 064, Folder 1)
    - HB586 - HB620. (Box 064, Folder 2)
    - HB622 - HB714. (Box 064, Folder 3)
    - HB726 - HB729. (Box 064, Folder 4)
    - HB730 - HB733. (Box 064, Folder 5)
    - HB742 - HB760. (Box 064, Folder 6)
    - HB761 - HB795. (Box 064, Folder 7)
    - HB796 - HB840. (Box 064, Folder 8)
    - HB849 - HB853. (Box 064, Folder 9)
    - HB854 - HB926. (Box 064, Folder 10)
    - HB937 - HB969. (Box 065, Folder 1)
    - HB992 - HB1037. (Box 065, Folder 2)
    - HB1038 - HB1062. (Box 065, Folder 3)
    - HB1066 - HB1112. (Box 065, Folder 4)
    - HB1115 - HB1146. (Box 065, Folder 5)
    - HB1147 - HB1162. (Box 065, Folder 6)
    - HB1165 - HB1300. (Box 065, Folder 7)
    - HB1307 - HB1330. (Box 065, Folder 8)
    - HB1349 - HB1391. (Box 065, Folder 9)
    - HB1394 - HB1464. (Box 065, Folder 10)
    - HB1472 - HB1493. (Box 065, Folder 11)
    - HB1501 - HB1545. (Box 066, Folder 1)
    - HB1557 - HB1587. (Box 066, Folder 2)
    - HB1589 - HB1607. (Box 066, Folder 3)
    - SJ4 - SJ106. (Box 066, Folder 4)
    - SJ120 - SJ185. (Box 066, Folder 5)
    - SB18 - SB42. (Box 066, Folder 6)
    - SB47 - SB116. (Box 066, Folder 7)
    - SB117 - SB167. (Box 066, Folder 8)
    - SB168 - SB190. (Box 066, Folder 9)
    - SB206 - SB217. (Box 066, Folder 10)
    - SB220 - SB250. (Box 066, Folder 11)
    - SB251 - SB289. (Box 066, Folder 12)
    - SB290 - SB317. (Box 067, Folder 1)
    - SB318 - SB414. (Box 067, Folder 2)
    - SB416 - SB428. (Box 067, Folder 3)
    - SB438 - SB494. (Box 067, Folder 4)
    - SB517 - SB543. (Box 067, Folder 5)
    - SB544 - SB580. (Box 067, Folder 6)
    - SB584 - SB632. (Box 067, Folder 7)
    - SB635 - SB663. (Box 067, Folder 8)
    - SB668 - SB730. (Box 067, Folder 9)
  - 2007 House and Senate Bills
    - HB1630 - HB1637. (Box 068, Folder 1)
    - HB1688 - HB1777. (Box 068, Folder 2)
    - HB1788 - HB1883. (Box 068, Folder 3)
    - HB1897 - HB1923. (Box 068, Folder 4)
    - HB1925 - HB1951. (Box 068, Folder 5)
    - HB1952 - HB1965. (Box 068, Folder 6)
    - HB1985 - HB2033. (Box 068, Folder 7)
    - HB2035 - HB2045. (Box 068, Folder 8)
    - HB2046 - HB2087. (Box 068, Folder 9)
    - HB2102 - HB2125. (Box 069, Folder 1)
    - HB2149 - HB2158. (Box 069, Folder 2)
    - HB2161 - HB2211. (Box 069, Folder 3)
    - HB2212 - HB2269. (Box 069, Folder 4)
    - HB2274 - HB2290. (Box 069, Folder 5)
    - HB2299 - HB2323. (Box 069, Folder 6)
    - HB2337 - HB2366. (Box 069, Folder 7)
    - HB2367 - HB2393. (Box 069, Folder 8)
    - HB2422 - HB2504. (Box 069, Folder 9)
    - HB2511 - HB2528. (Box 070, Folder 1)
    - HB2530 - HB2583. (Box 070, Folder 2)
    - HB2607 - HB2646. (Box 070, Folder 3)
    - HB2649 - HB2658. (Box 070, Folder 4)
    - HB2671 - HB2684. (Box 070, Folder 5)
    - HB2689 - HB2691. (Box 070, Folder 6)
    - HB2692 - HB2721. (Box 070, Folder 7)
    - HB2722 - HB2735. (Box 070, Folder 8)
    - HB2776 - HB2811. (Box 070, Folder 9)
    - HB2815 - HB2864. (Box 071, Folder 1)
    - HB2882 - HB2955. (Box 071, Folder 2)
    - HB2962 - HB3043. (Box 071, Folder 3)
    - HB3061 - HB3111. (Box 071, Folder 4)
    - HB3131 - HB3156. (Box 071, Folder 5)
    - HB3163 - HB3170. (Box 071, Folder 6)
    - HB3183 - HB3209. (Box 071, Folder 7)
    - SB737 - SB757. (Box 071, Folder 8)
    - SB763 - SB852. (Box 071, Folder 9)
    - SB856 - SB905. (Box 072, Folder 1)
    - SB917 - SB923. (Box 072, Folder 2)
    - SB928 - SB938. (Box 072, Folder 3)
    - SB944 - SB954. (Box 072, Folder 4)
    - SB958 - SB995. (Box 072, Folder 5)
    - SB996 - SB1041. (Box 072, Folder 6)
    - SB1052 - SB1097. (Box 072, Folder 7)
    - SB1103 - SB1112. (Box 072, Folder 8)
    - SB113. (Box 073, Folder 1)
    - SB1117 - SB1198. (Box 073, Folder 2)
    - SB1202 - SB1207. (Box 073, Folder 3)
    - SB1208 - SB1225. (Box 073, Folder 4)
    - SB1228 - SB1270. (Box 073, Folder 5)
    - SB1300 - SB1332. (Box 073, Folder 6)
    - SB1339 - SB1423. (Box 073, Folder 7)
  - 2008 House and Senate Bills
    - HB3 - HB78. (Box 074, Folder 1)
    - HB81 - HB130. (Box 074, Folder 2)
    - HB138 - HB149. (Box 074, Folder 3)
    - HB173 - HB216. (Box 074, Folder 4)
    - HB222 - HB250. (Box 074, Folder 5)
    - HB251 - HB276. (Box 074, Folder 6)
    - HB278 - HB312. (Box 074, Folder 7)
    - HB316 - HB383. (Box 074, Folder 8)
    - HB396 - HB403. (Box 074, Folder 9)
    - HB404 - HB480. (Box 074, Folder 10)
    - HB499 - HB500. (Box 075, Folder 1)
    - HB501 - HB518. (Box 075, Folder 2)
    - HB530 - HB572. (Box 075, Folder 3)
    - HB576 - HB584. (Box 075, Folder 4)
    - HB593 - HB605. (Box 075, Folder 5)
    - HB617 - HB696. (Box 075, Folder 6)
    - HB700 - HB729. (Box 075, Folder 7)
    - HB735 - HB752. (Box 075, Folder 8)
    - HB760. (Box 075, Folder 9)
    - HB760. (Box 076, Folder 1)
    - HB764 - HB807. (Box 076, Folder 2)
    - HB811 - HB825. (Box 076, Folder 3)
    - HB850 - HB896. (Box 076, Folder 4)
    - HB926 - HB1006. (Box 076, Folder 5)
    - HB1025 - HB1046. (Box 076, Folder 6)
    - HB1054 - HB1100. (Box 076, Folder 7)
    - HB1126 - HB1141. (Box 076, Folder 8)
    - HB1143 - HB1174. (Box 077, Folder 1)
    - HB1184 - HB1213. (Box 077, Folder 2)
    - HB1222 - HB1253. (Box 077, Folder 3)
    - HB1257 - HB1305. (Box 077, Folder 4)
    - HB1306 - HB1322. (Box 077, Folder 5)
    - HB1323 - HB1356. (Box 077, Folder 6)
    - HB1378 - HB1417. (Box 077, Folder 7)
    - HB1420 - HB1447. (Box 077, Folder 8)
    - HB1461 - HB1489. (Box 077, Folder 9)
    - HB1491 - HB1528. (Box 077, Folder 10)
    - HB1530 - HB1556. (Box 078, Folder 1)
    - SB14 - SB47. (Box 078, Folder 2)
    - SB58 - SB68. (Box 078, Folder 3)
    - SB72 - SB97. (Box 078, Folder 4)
    - SB100 - SB129. (Box 078, Folder 5)
    - SB134 - SB151. (Box 078, Folder 6)
    - SB155 - SB211. (Box 078, Folder 7)
    - SB212 - SB231. (Box 078, Folder 8)
    - SB241 - SB247. (Box 078, Folder 9)
    - SB249 - SB250. (Box 078, Folder 10)
    - SB251 - SB275. (Box 079, Folder 1)
    - SB276 - SB313. (Box 079, Folder 2)
    - SB313 - SB341. (Box 079, Folder 3)
    - SB344 - SB396. (Box 079, Folder 4)
    - SB397 - SB437. (Box 079, Folder 5)
    - SB440 - SB472. (Box 079, Folder 6)
    - SB479 - SB485. (Box 079, Folder 7)
    - SB486 - SB493. (Box 079, Folder 8)
    - SB494 - SB501. (Box 079, Folder 9)
    - SB503 - SB564. (Box 079, Folder 10)
    - SB568 - SB602. (Box 080, Folder 1)
    - SB620. (Box 080, Folder 2)
    - SB626 - SB657. (Box 080, Folder 3)
    - SB658 - SB702. (Box 080, Folder 4)
    - SB721 - SB788 and SB6018. (Box 080, Folder 5)
  - 2009 House and Senate Bills
    - HB1588 - HB1601. (Box 081, Folder 1)
    - HB1605 - HB1703. (Box 081, Folder 2)
    - HB1704 - HB1820. (Box 081, Folder 3)
    - HB1829 - HB1897. (Box 081, Folder 4)
    - HB1904 - HB1948. (Box 081, Folder 5)
    - HB1952 - HB2048. (Box 081, Folder 6)
    - HB2058 - HB2141. (Box 081, Folder 7)
    - HB2142 - HB2184. (Box 081, Folder 8)
    - HB2188 - HB2246. (Box 081, Folder 9)
    - HB2257 - HB2338. (Box 082, Folder 1)
    - HB2340 - HB2382. (Box 082, Folder 2)
    - HB2389 - HB2447. (Box 082, Folder 3)
    - HB2449 - HB2461. (Box 082, Folder 4)
    - HB2462 - HB2551. (Box 082, Folder 5)
    - HB2521 - HB2674. (Box 082, Folder 6)
    - SB807 - SB861. (Box 082, Folder 7)
    - SB870 - SB920. (Box 082, Folder 8)
    - SB921 - SB1007. (Box 082, Folder 9)
    - SB1011 - SB1032. (Box 083, Folder 1)
    - SB1034 - SB1068. (Box 083, Folder 2)
    - SB1075 - SB1099. (Box 083, Folder 3)
    - SB1106 - SB1122. (Box 083, Folder 4)
    - SB1128 - SB1179. (Box 083, Folder 5)
    - SB1180 - SB1207. (Box 083, Folder 6)
    - SB1228 - SB1276. (Box 083, Folder 7)
    - SB1282 - SB1334. (Box 083, Folder 8)
    - SB1340 - SB1454. (Box 083, Folder 9)
    - SB1458 - SB1543. (Box 083, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Legislative Files.
    - Legislative Handbook (2008), 2007. (Box 084, Folder 1)
    - Legislative Handbook (2008), 2007. (Box 084, Folder 2)
    - Legislative Proposals, 2007. (Box 084, Folder 3)
    - Legislative Proposals, 2007. (Box 084, Folder 4)
    - Legislative Proposals, 2007. (Box 084, Folder 5)
    - Legislative Proposals (2008), 2007. (Box 084, Folder 6)
    - Legislative Proposals (2008), 2007. (Box 084, Folder 7)
    - Legislative Proposals (2008), 2007. (Box 085, Folder 1)
    - Legislative Proposal (2009), 2008. (Box 085, Folder 2)
    - Legislative Proposal (2009), 2008. (Box 085, Folder 3)
    - Legislative Proposals - Social Services, Dept. of (2007), 2006. (Box 085, Folder 4)
    - Legislative Proposals - Social Services, Dept. of (2007), 2006. (Box 085, Folder 5)
    - Legislative Proposals - Social Services, Dept. of (2007), 2006. (Box 085, Folder 6)
    - Legislative Proposals - Social Services, Dept. of (2007), 2006. (Box 085, Folder 7)
    - Legislative Proposals - Social Services, Dept. of (2009), 2008. (Box 086, Folder 1)
    - Legislative Proposals - Social Services, Dept. of (2009), 2008. (Box 086, Folder 2)
    - Social Services, Dept. of, undated. (Box 086, Folder 3)
- Series VII. Planning and Budget Files - Assigned State Agencies, 2006-2007., Extent: .45 cu. ft. (1 box).
  Contains various budget-related files including those related to budget amendments for the 2006-2008 biennium, budget reductions in 2008, and the decision package for FY 2009-2010. The budget reduction plan includes line item reduction strategies for agencies under the purview of the Secretary of Health and Human Resources. The decision package funding requests and narrative justications for requests submitted by Health and Human Resources agencies.
  Arranged chronologically by year.
  - 2006-2008 Budget, 2006-2007. (Box 087, Folder 1)
  - 2006-2008 Budget Amendments, 2006. (Box 087, Folder 2)
  - 2008 Budget Reduction Plan, 2007. (Box 087, Folder 3)
  - 2009-2010 Budget, 2008. (Box 087, Folder 4)
  - Decision Package (FY2009-2010), 2007. (Box 087, Folder 5)
  - Decision Package (FY2009-2010), 2007. (Box 087, Folder 6)
  - Decision Package (FY2009-2010), 2007. (Box 087, Folder 7)
  - Decision Package (FY2009-2010), 2007. (Box 087, Folder 8)
- Series VIII. Public Relations, Activties and Visits, 2006-2007., Extent: .225 cu. ft. (1 box).
  Contains records that document the activities of the Secretary of Health and Human Resources. Included are talking points on various subjects such as the uninsured population, aging, and workforce shortages. Also included are folders related to speaking engagements and Virginia's Royal Welcome during which Queen Elizabeth II visited Virginia.
  - Talking Points, 2006; undated. (Box 088, Folder 1)
  - Virginia Health Care Foundation, 2007. (Box 088, Folder 2)
  - Virginia Public Health Association, 2007. (Box 088, Folder 3)
  - Virginia's Royal Welcome (Queen's Visit), 2007. (Box 088, Folder 4)
- Series IX. Special Projects and Studies, 2006-2009., Extent: 1.8 cu. ft. (4 boxes).
  Contains a variety of files pertaining to special projects and task forces such as the Governor's Commission on Sexual Violence (formed through Executive Order 38), the Health Benefits Taskforce which documents the cost of providing health care to those in the custody of the Department of Juvenile Justice and the Department of Corrections, the Joint Commission on Health Care, and an organizational assessment of several Health and Human Resources agencies. Also included are Virginia Congressional Delegation briefing packets that detail secretarial priorities for members of the United States Congress from Virginia districts.
  - Attorney General's Government and Regulatory Reform Task Force - Final Report, 2009. (Box 089, Folder 1)
  - Commissioner's Infant Mortality Work Group - Report to Governor, 2009. (Box 089, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Briefing Forms - FY2009 (multiple agencies), undated. (Box 089, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Delegation Briefing, 2006 February. (Box 089, Folder 3)
  - Congressional Delegation Briefing, 2006 March. (Box 089, Folder 4)
  - Congressional Delegation Briefing, 2006 March. (Box 089, Folder 5)
  - Congressional Delegation Briefing, 2008. (Box 089, Folder 6)
  - Congressional Delegation Briefing, 2009. (Box 089, Folder 7)
  - Congressional Delegation Briefing Requests, 2008. (Box 089, Folder 8)
  - Governor's Cabinet Tabletop Exercise Situation Manual, 2008. (Box 089, Folder 9)
  - Governor's Commission on Sexual Violence - Resource Notebook, 2006. (Box 089, Folder 9)
  - Governor's Commission on Sexual Violence - Resource Notebook, 2006. (Box 089, Folder 10)
  - Health Benefits Taskforce Data - Corrections, Dept. of, 2008. (Box 090, Folder 1)
  - Health Benefits Taskforce Data - Juvenile Justice, Dept. of, 2008. (Box 090, Folder 2)
  - Health Benefits Taskforce Data - Juvenile Justice, Dept. of, 2008. (Box 090, Folder 3)
  - Health Benefits Taskforce Data - Juvenile Justice, Dept. of, 2008. (Box 090, Folder 4)
  - Healthcare Workforce Data Center Advisory Council - Initial Orientation Meeting, 2008. (Box 090, Folder 5)
  - Joint Commission on Health Care, 2006 August. (Box 090, Folder 6)
  - Joint Commission on Health Care, 2006 September. (Box 090, Folder 7)
  - Joint Commission on Health Care, 2006 October. (Box 090, Folder 8)
  - Joint Commission on Health Care, 2007. (Box 090, Folder 9)
  - Legal Exercise Situation Manual, 2007. (Box 090, Folder 10)
  - National Association of Social Workers - Presentation, 2008. (Box 091, Folder 1)
  - National Association of Social Workers - Presentation, 2008. (Box 091, Folder 2)
  - Nursing Education Capacity Summitt, 2008. (Box 091, Folder 3)
  - Nursing Education Capacity Summitt, 2008. (Box 091, Folder 4)
  - Organizational Assessment of VDH, DSS, DMHMRSAS (North Highland), 2008. (Box 091, Folder 5)
  - Organizational Assessment of VDH, DSS, DMHMRSAS with Appendices (North Highland), 2008. (Box 091, Folder 6)
  - Organizational Assessment of VDH, DSS, DMHMRSAS with Appendices (North Highland), 2008. (Box 091, Folder 7)
  - Portfolio Management and Prosight Training for the Secretariats, 2007. (Box 091, Folder 8)
  - Secure Commonwealth Panel, 2006. (Box 092, Folder 1)
  - Secure Commonwealth Panel, 2006. (Box 092, Folder 2)
  - State Workforce Initiatives, 2006. (Box 092, Folder 3)
  - State Workforce Initiatives, 2006. (Box 092, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Commission on Immigration, 2007-2008. (Box 092, Folder 5)
  - Virginia Commission on Immigration, 2007-2008. (Box 092, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Commission on Immigration, 2007-2008. (Box 092, Folder 7)